>> 演讲者 1: 关于提升的最后一个注释。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: One last note on hoisting.
有些人以前听说过
Some of you have heard the phrase before,
而不会对块作用域进行提升。
let doesn't hoist with
respect to the block scope.
因为当你写这样的代码时，第 2 行的老师分配
Because when you write code like this,
the teacher assignment on line 2
会抛出错误，所谓的 TDZ 错误，时间死区错误，好吗 ?
will throw an error, a so-called TDZ
error, temporal dead zone error, okay?
这个说法，不要再吊起，
This statement, let doesn't hoist,
是善意的但却不准确
is meant in good spirit,
but it is inaccurate.
我可以向你证明这不准确因为我们已经看到
And I can prove to you that it's
inaccurate, because we've already seen
一个吊起的概念，我们已经看到了一个代码的例子。
a notion of hoisting and
we've already seen a code example.
如果老师没被提升到现在还不存在
Where if teacher didn't get hoisted and
therefore didn't exist in the scope yet,
那节目就会有不同的表现
then the program would behave differently.
这是一个例子。
So here is such an example.
在此代码中，如果第 5 行上的老师未托管，
In this code,
if the teacher on line 5 did not host,
那么第 4 行应该打印出 "凯尔"
then line 4 should print out "Kyle".
因为第四行没有老师，应该去外域，
Because there is no teacher as of line 4
and it should go to the outer scope and
从第 1 行查找变量。
find the variable from line 1.
但此代码仍会抛出 TDZ 错误，并且
But this code still throws a TDZ error,
and
它仍然抛出 TDZ 错误的原因是，允许和 consts 仍处于挂起状态。
the reason it still throws a TDZ error
is because lets and consts still hoist.
但他们的吊重机是有区别的
But there is a difference
between how they hoist.
第一个，让和应征者只提升到一个街区，而桨则提升到一个功能。
Number one, lets and consts only hoist to
a block, whereas vars hoist to a function.
但第二，这才是最重要的事情，
But number two, and
this is the more important thing,
var 和 let const 之间的差异是 var在创建时
the difference between var and
let const is that var, when it creates
在您的作用域的编译时间内，它的变量和计划。
its variables and has the plan during
the compile time for your scope.
它说在这个范围里会有一个叫老师的变量
And it says there's gonna be a variable
called teacher in this scope,
它还表示作用域启动时，将其初始化为未定义。
it also says when the scope starts,
initialize it to undefined.
>> 扬声器 1: 当将变量放入其块作用域时，它表示
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: When let hoists its
variables into its block scope it says
创建一个名为 " 老师 " 的位置，但不进行初始化。
create a location called teacher,
but don't initialize it.
它处于未初始化状态，
It is in an uninitialized state,
未初始化的情况与未定义的不同。
uninitialized being
different than undefined.
未初始化表示您无法触摸它。
Uninitialized meaning
you can't touch it yet.
它不会被初始化直到在那个块中运行
And it doesn't get initialized until
in that block you run across the let or
const 声明。
the const declaration.
>演讲者 1: 所以这绝对是吊重机，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: So
these absolutely do hoist,
这就是为什么我们仍然有一个 TDZ 错误，只是它们没有被初始化。
which is why we still get a TDZ error,
it's just that they don't get initialized.
>> 演讲者 1: 顺便说一下，我有时会问为什么 TDZ 出错?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: By the way,
I sometimes get asked why the TDZ error?
他们为什么会这样做呢 ?
Why did they make this an error?
这比你能意识到的要多
It is much more nuance
than you might realize.
我曾认为此场景中 TDZ 错误的主要原因
I used to believe that the primary reason
for the TDZ error in this scenario
本质上是 TC39 试图对你进行社会改造
was that, essentially,
TC39 was trying to socially engineer you.
要停止对先前在作用域中的变量进行分配，请将其分配到您已声明它们的位置。
To stop assigning to variables earlier in
scopes than where you've declared them.
我也大体同意，但是当语言如此的时候，我有点恼火。
Which again, I generally agree with, but
I'm a little annoyed when a language is so
都是很有意见的好吗
heavy handed with its opinions, okay?
所以我一般都同意，我也习惯了
So I generally would agree with that,
and I used to just sort of chaff
他们会逼我做出这个决定的
at the idea that they would have
forced me into that decision.
但事实证明这比这更微妙
But turns out it's much
more nuance than that.
这几乎是学术上的细微差别
This is almost the height
of kind of academic nuance,
但我会和你分享让你能全面了解 TDZ的情况
but I'll share it with you so
that you have the full perspective on TDZ.
TDZ 存在的原因根本不存在， TDZ 因为常量而存在。
The reason TDZ exists is not even for
let, TDZ exists because of const.
请考虑在块作用域中附加的常量。
Think about const being attached
inside of a block scope.
想象如果常量初始化为未定义的。
Imagine if const initialized
itself to undefined.
然后在一个块的第 1 行中，您对该变量进行了 console.log 。
And then on line 1 of a block,
you did console.log of that variable and
你看到它未定义，然后你看到它的值是 42。
you saw it undefined, and
then later you saw it with the value 42.
从技术上来说，这个常量在两个不同的时间会有两个不同的值，
Technically, that const would have had two
different values at two different times,
在学术上违背了一个人的概念
which academically violates
the concept of a const.
所以他们说我们要防止你提前在范围内访问一个变量
So they said we have to prevent you from
accessing a variable earlier in the scope
只有一个和一个只有一个值的时候
than when it's been assigned that one and
only one value, so
你不能在中间状态下观察它
that you can't observe it
in that intermediate state.
于是他们发明了 TDZ for const 然后他们说
So they invented TDZ for
const and then they said, well,
如果我们要为康斯特做我们也可以这么做
if we're gonna do it for const,
we might as well do it for let.
>> 扬声器 2: [INAUDIBLE] >> 演讲者 1: 这是事实。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [INAUDIBLE]
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: That's the fact.
因此，让我们有一个 TDZ ，因为在学术上需要一个 TDZ。
So let's have a TDZ,
because const academically needed a TDZ.
我的建议
My advice?
就像我之前说的把你的一切都放了或者你真的坚持
Just exactly as I said before, put all
your lets, or if you really insist on
冒号把它们放在最上面的第一条线上
colons, put them all at the very top
of the block, on the very first line.
然后你就无法观察到 TDZ了
And then you'll never be
able to observe a TDZ.
别把它们串在这些范围内，这是个坏主意。
[LAUGH] Don't string them throughout
those scopes, that's a bad idea.
这样我们就不说话了
Just so that we don't say things,
我有一些人在这些问题上有时会不同意我的意见
and I have people that sometimes will
disagree with me on these topics.
所以我们在这个话题上是完全清楚的，
And just so that we're entirely
clear on this topic of whether or
不要让它吊起
not let doesn't hoist.
实际上，在规范中，它表示变量是在它们的
Here is actually in the spec where it says
that the variables are created when their
包含词法环境的实例。
containing lexical
environment is instantiated.
当对词法绑定进行求值时，不会在创建变量时进行求值。
When the lexical binding is evaluated,
not when the variable's created.
所以它就在这个规范中。
So it's right there in the spec.
最近有一场大的推特战争人们告诉我我错了
There was a big Twitter war recently where
people were telling me that I was wrong on
这就是它在规范中的内容
this, and that's what it says in the spec.
虽然我们可能喜欢不同的心理模型
Even though we might like to have
different mental models for it,
这就是它在规范中的内容
it's what it says in the spec.
>> 扬声器 3: 为什么不提升函数表达式 ?
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Why do function
expressions not hoist?
在编译时间与运行时间的上下文中，我们能否讨论这个问题 ?
Could we talk about that in the context
of compile time versus run time?
>> 演讲者 1: 好的。 >> 扬声器 3: 发生的情况
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Okay.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Things that happen for
函数表达式。
the function expression.
>> 演讲者 1: 是的，这是个好问题。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Yeah,
that's a good question.
所以我不知道我是否能找到这张幻灯片但如果你还记得
So I don't know if I could find the slide,
but if you recall back,
当您将函数表达式分配给变量时，
when you assign a function
expression to a variable,
变量修饰本身已挂起，但分配是运行时事件。
the variables decoration itself hoisted,
but the assignment is a run time thing.
想象一下 JavaScript 对可执行代码进行重新排序的想法。
Imagine mentally the idea of JavaScript
reordering your executable code.
我们会很快陷入混乱对吧
We would quickly descend into chaos,
right?
因此，可执行代码在概念上不能被重新排序，只是声明式代码。
So executable code can't conceptually
be reordered, only declarative code.
所以我们可以说有一个叫 X的东西，或者说一个叫老师的东西，
So we can say that there is a thing
called X, or a thing called teacher, and
甚至有一个叫 X 的东西会提到这个功能的范围。
even there is a thing called X that's
gonna reference this function scope.
我们可以宣言性地做到这一点。
We can do that declaratively.
但如果它是可以明显观察到的
But if it's something that is literally
observable as an execution operation
在一个程序中，不能在编译时发生，不能在编译时发生。
in a program, that can't hoist,
that can't happen at compile time.
它必须在运行时发生。
It has to happen at run time.
它必须发生在它通常会发生的程序中。
And it has to happen where in
the program it would normally happen.
否则，您永远无法预测您的 JavaScript。
Otherwise you would never be
able to predict your JavaScript.
>> 扬声器 3: 在运行时，如果正在分配函数表达式
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: So at run time if you're
assigning a function expression
以可变目标为目标
to a variable targeting,
那么是在该运行时过程中创建的新作用域吗 ?
then is a new scope created
during that run time process?
>> 演讲者 1: 好的，让我们说清楚。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: Well, let's be clear.
你在问一个非常重要的问题，但这两个层次都在上面。
You're asking a very important question,
but there's this two layered on top.
第一，编译时间仍处理该功能。
Number one,
compile time still handled the function.
它没有推迟处理
It didn't defer handling,
不像说我不知道那里有什么功能
it's not like it said I don't know
that there's a function there.
它还是一个功能，还得有一个计划，
It's still a function,
it still has to have a plan,
一张地图上彩色的弹珠和其他的东西
a map for its colored marbles and
all of that other stuff.
没有发生的是在编译时没有得到
What didn't happen is it didn't get,
at compile time,
与范围中的某个标识关联，但它仍被编译好吗 ?
associated with some identifier in the
scope, but it still got compiled, okay?
这就是第一
So that's number one.
第二，所有功能都有其范围的计划，直到
Number two, all functions have a plan for
their scope, until,
每次被处决的时候
and every time they get executed.
所以当它被执行时它是一个声明还是一个表达式，当它被执行的时候
So whether it was a declaration or an
expression, when it gets executed is when
整个映射器计划变成了一个真实的记忆
that whole mapper plan becomes
a real thing in memory, and
每次执行死刑都是如此
every time it gets executed,
that is the case.
所以这在声明和表达之间是不一样的。
So that's no different between
declarations or expressions.